davidjones.com 2019-12-15

# Privacy & Security

#### David Jones Privacy Policy December 2019

David Jones Pty Ltd (Australia) and David Jones (New Zealand) Pty Limited ( **David Jones** ) recognises the importance of protecting the privacy of our customers and other third parties who provide their personal information to us.

Our policy for dealing with your personal information is explained below ( **Privacy Policy** ).

Our Privacy Policy was last updated in December 2019 and includes disclosure of thmatters set out in the Australian Privacy Principles and the New Zealand Privacy Principles.

#### Personal information we collect

When used in this policy, “personal information” has the meaning given to that term in the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth) for our Australian operations and the Privacy Act 1993 for our New Zealand operations. Personal information generally includes any information that can be used to personally identify you.

We use Google Analytics Advertising Features to promote our Services. Google and other third parties collect data about traffic to this site via advertising cookies and identifiers. This enables us to display ads on other sites that are relevant to you, based on your previous visits to this site. If you would like to prevent your data from being used by Google Analytics, please click here: https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout. Alternatively, you can find out how Google Analytics uses data when you use our partners’ sites or apps, at www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners

The personal information we collect from you is what is reasonably necessary for our business functions. We may collect the following types of personal information from you:

  * name;
  * residential or business address;
  * email address;
  * post code;
  * gender;
  * age and date of birth;
  * signature;
  * telephone number;
  * proof of identity, such as your drivers licence or passport number;
  * a photograph or video surveillance recording of you if you are physically present in our stores;
  * in relation to a David Jones American Express Card (for our Australian operations), information as further set out in the David Jones American Express Joint Privacy Policy; or
  * if you are a candidate for employment, we may collect other information as further set out in our application forms or during the recruitment process. This may include information relating to your employment history, working eligibility rights, suitability for the role you are applying for, and your referee details

#### Other information

We may also collect information from you that is not personal information because it does not identify you personally. This information is normally retained with your personal information and may include:

  * your shopping preferences and a list of products and services you have purchased from David Jones. This may include your shopping history, product types, departments, specifications, sizes, dimensions, colours, occasion date, or other attributes of products and services we have provided to you or may provide to you in the future;
  * information we require to deliver, service or fulfil warranty obligations for products or services;
  * your marketing preferences, including the type of marketing materials you wish to receive and the method of delivery (email, SMS, direct mail, or other);
  * if you are a member of David Jones Rewards, your membership number, and reward redemption history for David Jones special rewards or services;
  * information you provide to us via our customer service centre, website, application forms, or directly to team members within our stores in relation to our products and services;
  * device identification information when you use a computer, mobile phone, smart phone, tablet, or other device to access our WIFI service or interact with us through our online store (www.davidjones.com). This information may include session cookies, your device IMEI number, IP address or MAC address; and
  * information collected via our secure payment processing systems.

#### Purpose of collection of your personal information

We collect your personal information for the primary purpose of being able to sell and promote our products to you . In addition we collect your personal information so that we can carry out the following actions (each a **Purpose** ):

  * to provide you with products and services that you have requested from us;
  * to communicate with you, including about products and services, competition results, special offers, and events which might interest you (including any associated David Jones Rewards special offers and rewards);
  * to answer your questions and provide you with information or advice;
  * to interact with you via social media and digital marketing;
  * to create orders, transaction records, agreements for the sale of products or services, accounts, tax invoices or receipts;
  * provide your personal information to third parties that assist us in providing products and services you have requested, such as delivery service providers and fulfilment managers;
  * carry out administration, marketing, planning, fraud and loss prevention activities, procurement, product and service development, quality control and research to improve the way David Jones and its related bodies corporate and service providers provide products and services to you;
  * to consider and respond to complaints made by you;
  * to comply with laws or regulations or to comply with any directions given by regulators or authorities; or
  * if you are a candidate for employment, to assess your suitability for a position at David Jones

#### If we are unable to collect your personal information

If we are unable to collect your personal information, some or all of the following may occur:

  * we may be unable to provide products or services to you, to the requested standard or at all;
  * we may be unable to communicate with you to provide information about products and services that you have purchased from us, or may intend to purchase in the future;
  * we may be unable to tailor the content of our marketing communications to suit your preferences;
  * your experience when interacting with us may be delayed or not as efficient as you may expect; or
  * if you are a candidate for employment, we may not be able to process your application for a position at David Jones

#### Pseudonyms and anonymity

While you have the discretion to use a pseudonym or remain anonymous when dealing with us, the use of pseudonyms may prevent us from being able to provide you with products and services or for other purposes described in this Privacy Policy. This is particularly the case where you order goods which need to be delivered to your postal address, or goods subject to age restrictions such as the supply of alcohol.

#### Cookies

Cookies are small pieces of information captured when your device is used to access online content. We use cookies to ensure a more streamlined online shopping experience, to identify and store your personal preferences without the need for you to save them and provide you with appropriate and relevant promotions. We may use temporary (session) cookies or permanent cookies when you access our web site, which allows us to recognise your browser and track the web pages you have visited. You can switch off cookies by adjusting the settings on your web browser.

#### Unsolicited information

We will endeavour to only take information from you which is reasonably necessary for our business functions. If you send us personal information that we have not requested, or we determine that the personal information you have provided to us is not reasonably necessary or directly related to any of our business functions or activities, we may de-identify or delete this information without notifying you to protect your privacy.

#### How we collect your personal information

Normally we collect information from you directly, unless it is unreasonable or impracticable to do so.

Collection of your personal information can occur through the following interactions:

  * when you join David Jones Rewards by subscribing to receive marketing emails;
  * when you register with us by creating an account, or subscribe to our marketing programs;
  * when you access and use our website or WiFi services, or interact with us via social media or digital media;
  * when you provide information to our team members;
  * when you complete purchase orders, registrations, requests or applications for our products or services (by phone, in person or electronically);
  * when you communicate with us directly (by email, telephone, direct mail or any other means);
  * when you interact with us during promotions, competitions, special events, or by using devices within our stores; or
  * if you are a candidate for employment, when you complete forms in relation to the recruitment and selection process, for the purpose of assessment.

We may also collect personal information about you from the following third parties:

  * retail brands and suppliers who provide goods and services within our stores. This may include beauty, fashion, electrical, home wares and other suppliers who provide products and services to you on our behalf;
  * credit reporting agencies and related entities when you apply for a David Jones American Express Card or David Jones StoreCard, as further set out in the David Jones American Express Joint Privacy Policy; and
  * if you are a candidate for employment, we may collect information about you from your nominated referees, where you have authorised us to do so.

#### How we hold your personal information

We may hold your personal information in either electronic or hard copy form. If you provide information to us electronically we retain this information in our computer systems and databases. This includes computer software programs, internet servers, and hosted internet solutions provided by third parties. If you provide information to us in hard copy (paper) this information is normally retained in our files and a copy is made to our electronic files.

#### Security

We use industry standard security measures to safeguard and protect your information. This includes taking reasonable steps to ensure your personal information is protected from misuse, loss, unauthorised access, modification or disclosure.

#### Disclosure of your personal information

Your personal information may be disclosed in connection with any Purpose to any of the following:

  * our employees, contractors or service providers, to the extent reasonably necessary to fulfil our obligations to you. This may include internet service providers, IT systems administrators, mailing houses, couriers, payment processors, and data entry service providers;
  * retail brands and suppliers who provide goods and services within our stores. This may include beauty, fashion, electrical, home wares and other suppliers who provide products and services to you on our behalf;
  * our related companies and brands, including Country Road Group Pty Ltd (Mimco, Witchery, Trenery, Politix and Country Road) and Woolworths Holdings Limited (incorporated in South Africa);
  * our business advisors, including lawyers, accountants or other professional service providers, to the extent reasonably required;
  * suppliers and other third parties with whom we have commercial relationships, for business, marketing and related purposes;
  * any of our related Australian and New Zealand entities;
  * if you are a candidate for an employment position involving a third party with whom we have an agreement, to that third party to assess your application;
  * if required by law, to any person authorised by such law. This may include the police service, ambulance service, or government departments or regulators within Australia or New Zealand in connection with law enforcement activities; and
  * for any other purpose permitted by law.

Your personal information will not be shared, sold, rented or disclosed other than as described in this Privacy Policy.

#### Direct Marketing and David Jones Rewards

We may send you direct marketing communications and information about products and services offered by us or our retail brands, partners or suppliers via the channels you have nominated. This may include, but is not limited to, email, SMS, regular mail, social media and other digital channels. If you have indicated a preference for a method of communication, we will endeavour to use that method wherever practical to do so. By consenting to receive email marketing communications from David Jones, you may also receive access to a range of exclusive offers and rewards not available to the general public **(David Jones Rewards)**. If you are currently receiving David Jones emails, you will automatically be a member of, and receive emails about, David Jones Rewards. You can join David Jones Rewards by subscribing to marketing emails from David Jones. You can do this by creating an online profile and opting in to receive emails from David Jones, or by providing your email address instore. All the benefits from David Jones Rewards will be delivered to you via email, including rewards and exclusive offers. You may opt out of receiving marketing communications at any time by responding via the channel in which you received the marketing communication, or by contacting us (see contact information below). You can unsubscribe from emails by clicking the unsubscribe link on the footer of the email communication you have received. You may also update your personal information by editing your online profile. Please note that if you unsubscribe from emails, you will be unsubscribing from David Jones Rewards and all emails from David Jones. You may also receive marketing communications by post, email, SMS , direct and digital channels from our retail brands, partners and suppliers who provide goods and services within our stores, but this will only occur where you have requested that type of information from us or from a third party within our stores. We do not provide your personal information to any other organisations for the purposes of direct marketing.

#### Information given by you to other parties

So that we can provide a wide range of products and services to you, third parties offering products and services may be operating in our stores from time to time. If you provide personal information to a third party other than David Jones, please contact that third party directly in relation to the handling of your personal information.

#### How you may access your information

You may access your personal information (where it is held online) by logging into our portal at www.davidjones.com or through the David Jones website.

You may also access your personal information held by David Jones by making a request to us.

Email: [privacy@davidjones.com.au](mailto:privacy@davidjones.com.au) or [contactus@davidjones.com.au](mailto:contactus@davidjones.com.au)

Mail:

**The Privacy Officer**  
David Jones Pty Ltd  
Legal Services  
Building 2, 572 Swan St  
Burnley VIC 3121

Normally we will provide a record of your personal information to you via your preferred contact method (phone, email or mail), and we may charge a fee.

If your request is unlawful or may interfere with the privacy of others we may reasonably refuse to provide access to your personal information.

#### Correction of your personal information

If you would like us to update or amend your personal information, please contact us and we will make the requested amendments.

We may ask you to verify your identity to ensure that personal information we hold is not improperly accessed.

#### Complaints

If you feel your privacy has been breached, please contact us using the contact information above setting out the circumstances and reasons for your complaint.

Our team members will acknowledge receipt of your complaint within 24 hours, and will normally respond to your request within 5 business days. If your complaint is complicated or requires further investigation our response may take additional time to finalise.

We will respond to you by your preferred contact method if you have indicated one.

#### Overseas disclosure of personal information

We may disclose your personal information to third parties and service providers located overseas in connection with a Purpose.

We take reasonable steps to ensure that the overseas recipients of your personal information do not breach the privacy obligations relating to your personal information.

We may disclose your personal information to the following locations:

  * the **United States of America** , **Canada** and **Japan** \- for database management services in connection with our marketing, social media and data management programs
  * the **United Kingdom** \- for order management and processing for international hamper orders;
  * **New Zealand** \- for payment processing of online orders, for information held by our related company, Country Road Group Pty Ltd, or in relation to David Jones stores situated in New Zealand;
  * **the country in which you nominate as a delivery address** – for order fulfilment (if not within Australia), if you have ordered products or services from our online store and require delivery to an address in that foreign country;
  * **South Africa** \- for information held by David Jones' parent company; and
  * **each country identified in the David Jones American Express Joint Privacy Policy** , for personal information held in connection with your David Jones American Express Card.

#### Other services

We may offer seasonal or temporary services, promotions, social media events, products, competitions or displays such as photo booths or other promotional events from time to time ( **Other Services** ). Our Privacy Policy will apply to those Other Services but we may have additional terms which apply. Any additional terms will be made available to you when you are utilising our Other Services.

#### Contacting us

If you would like to contact us in relation to this Privacy Policy or your personal information please contact us at:

Mail:

**The Privacy Officer**  
David Jones Pty Ltd  
Legal Services  
Building 2, 572 Swan St  
Melbourne VIC 3121

We may update our Privacy Policy from time to time. Amendments will be published on our web page www.davidjones.com/information/privacy-and-security

#### Candidates and employees

If you are a candidate for employment, you may alternatively contact [careers@davidjones.com.au](mailto:careers@davidjones.com.au) in relation to this Privacy Policy or to access, update or amend your personal information.

This Privacy Policy does not apply to current and former employees of David Jones Pty Ltd. If you are a current or former employee and have a query about your personal information, please contact your Human Resources Representative.
